<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<task id="deployments">
  <title>Deployments</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>
        A Deployment within the OpenStack Queuing Solution (OQS) is a
        representation of vENM/cENM in terms of the OpenStack Cloud it will be
        installed in.
      </p>
      <p>
        Deployments are added to OQS queue using the OQS REST API as part of
        the automated CI/CD pipeline. Information on a Deployment is accessed
        within the view-page of its Parent Pod.<br/>
        <b>NOTE:</b> Admin users are only allowed to delete a Deployment.<br/>
        Two ways to delete Deployments using the UI, on a Pod view page:
        <ul>
          <li>All Pod's Deployments by clicking "Delete All Deployments" button (seen by Admin users only) at top of the page.</li>
          <li>Individual Pod Deployments by clicking "Delete" button under Action(s) column on the Finished Deployments table.</li>
        </ul>
        Here, Deployments are split between 3 tables:
      </p>
      <ol>
        <li>
          <b>Queued Deployments:</b> This table lists CI/CD pipelines that
          are currently waiting in the queue before being allowed to proceed.
          Once added to OQS, a Deployment joins the Parent-Pods queue and will
          remain queued while no work-tokens are available. If the Parent Pod's
          queuing-enabled toggle is set to false, the Deployment will also remain
          'Queued', regardless of available work-tokens. Information provided on the
          'Queued Deployments' table include Deployment name, job-type, duration
          of time spent queuing and the specific time queuing began.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Active Deployments:</b> This table lists Deployment CI/CD pipelines
          that are currently active. A Deployment becomes 'Active' when it
          is in first place of the queue and a work-token is available. Once
          'Active', the Deployments CI/CD pipeline can proceed. Information
          provided on the 'Active Deployments' table include Deployment name,
          job-type, duration of time spent running its job workflow, and the
          duration of time left until the Deployment times out. NOTE: A custom
          timeout duration value for a specific Deployment instance(s) can be
          set via the REST API using the 'customTimeout' parameter, which supersedes
          the timeout duration values configured at the generic Pod level.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Finished Deployments:</b> This table lists Deployment CI/CD
          pipelines that have finished running, whether successfully
          or with failures. Successful Deployments are greyed out while failed
          Deployments are displayed in red. Information provided on the 'Finished
          Deployments' table include Deployment name, job-type, job completion
          status type (Success/Failure), total queuing duration and total
          running duration.
        </li>
      </ol>

      <p><b>Objective</b></p>
      <p>Edit the Status of an Queued or Active Deployment in a Pod.</p>
      <p>The Queued/Active Deployments status within its associated Pod can be changed from Queued/Active to either one of the following options:</p>
      <ul>
        <li>Finished</li>
        <li>Failed</li>
        <li>Timed-out</li>
      </ul>
      <p>
        When the Deployment status has been changed,
        the Deployment will move from the Queued/Active Deployments to the Finished Deployments.<br/>
        <b>NOTE:</b> Once a Deployments status has been changed it can not be reverted.
      </p>

      <p><b>Note:</b>
        The status of Active can only be changed by user with Admin user privileges.
      </p>
      <p><b>Outline</b>
        <ol>
          <li>
            <xref href="#loginToOQS">Log-In to the OQS</xref>
          </li>
          <li>
            <xref href="#openPodView">Open the Pod View Page</xref>
          </li>
          <li>
            <xref href="#viewDeploymentDetails">View Deployment Details</xref>
          </li>
          <li>
            <xref href="#editQueueStatus">Edit Deployment Status</xref>
          </li>
          <li>
            <xref href="#saveDetails">Save</xref>
          </li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </context>

    <steps>
      <step id="loginToOQS">
        <cmd>Log-In to the OQS</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            Select the User tab in the nav bar, then select <b>"login"</b>.
            On submission of the required user login credentials, the user will
            be re-directed to the main page.
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="openPodList">
        <cmd>Open the Pod View Page</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            Click on the Pods tab in the nav bar and then select
            <b>"List View"</b>. Click the <b>View</b> button on the Pod row associated with the Deployment to edit.
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="viewDeploymentDetails">
        <cmd>View Deployment Details</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Open the Pod View page, and from the Queued/Active Deployments table click on the Deployment row's Action button <b>Edit Status</b> to open the edit status modal form.</p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="editQueueStatus">
        <cmd>Edit Deployment Status</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>From the <b>Status</b> dropdown menu, select one of the following statuses:</p>
          <ul>
            <li>Finished</li>
            <li>Failed</li>
            <li>Timed-out</li>
          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="saveDetails">
        <cmd>Save Details</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            Click the <b>Save</b> button, the Deployment Status will be updated.
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>

    <result>
      <p>
        The user will be redirected back to the Pod view page where it is
        possible to view recently updated Deployment information.
        The Deployment will be moved from Queued/Active Deployments table to Finished Deployments table
        and Metrics will show the updated statistics based on updated Deployment status.
      </p>
    </result>

  </taskbody>
</task>
