<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<task id="logs">
  <title>Historical Logs</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>
        A Historical Log within the OpenStack Queuing Solution is a representation of
        all actions performed on a specific Pod / Deployment within the OQS.
        Selecting the "Historical Log" option in the nav-bar provides users the option
        to view either Pods or Deployments logs list view.
      </p>

      <p><b>Object Logs List View</b></p>
      <p>
        The list page provides a list-view for Pods / Deployments logs, providing information on
        each object. The objects are split between two tables: "Live" and "Deleted". "Live" objects
        are ones that still exist within the main Database whilst "Deleted" ones have been removed
        from the Database.
      </p>
      <p>
        Each table provides basic information about each object where applicable such as
        Object ID, Object name, when it was created and by whom, as well as when it was deleted and
        by whom. A search field exists for filtering the tables by specific Object values. The tables
        are also sortable by any of the parameter values.
      </p>
      <p>
        A 'view log' action button exists for each object in the tables and allows a user to access
        an Objects log-view page that provides more detailed information on actions performed to
        the individual Object.
      </p>

      <p><b>Object Log View</b></p>
      <p>
        The log-view page provides a list of logs stating what actions were performed on a specific
        Pod or Deployment object. The first log states who created the object and when, with a
        "Download JSON" button so that the user can download a JSON file of the object as it existed
        when it was created. For each individual update performed on an object, the following is
        provided:
      </p>
      <ol>
        <li>
          Who performed the update. (Selecting the Updater's name opens a 'create email' panel so
          that the user can contact the updater if needs be.)
        </li>
        <li>
          The time and date that the update occurred on.
        </li>
        <li>
          A table that lists and details each specific change made to the object during that update.
        </li>
        <li>
          A "Download JSON" button that will download a JSON file of the object as it existed when
          this update occurred.
        </li>
      </ol>
      <p>
        <b>Note:</b> The Objects Log order for the Updates section is latest to oldest by date time.
        If the object has been deleted from the database, a final log will state by whom and when
        the deletion occurred. A "Download JSON" button is also provided here so that the user can
        download a JSON file of the object as it existed before it was deleted.
      </p>

      <p><b>Deleted Artifacts Logs Retention Policy</b></p>
      <lines>
        The deleted Artifacts logs are only kept up to six months, anything older than six months will be permanently deleted from the database.
        This deletion process is scheduled at start of each month.
      </lines>

      <p><b>Search Filter in Logs</b></p>
      <p>
        As every single artifact's history is arranged and sorted by time, it is difficult to find a specific key or value
        in an entire artifact's history. This functionality provides the ability to search any keys or values within each
        updated log in the entire artifact's history. Once the user inputs the search-query and clicks the corresponding
        button to search by either key or value, the records are filtered down to only those with any key/values that match
        the provided search-query. Click the clear button to delete the search pattern and get the entire history back to the page.
      </p>
      <p>
        <b> Note: To search for Dates, use YYYY-MM-YY format. e.g. 2022-02-02. </b>
      </p>
    </context>
  </taskbody>
</task>
