<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<concept id="NotificationBar">
  <title> Notification Bar</title>
  <conbody>
  <ul>
    <li><xref type="concept" href="#overview">Overview</xref></li>
    <li><xref type="concept" href="#purpose">Purpose of this feature</xref></li>
    <li><xref type="concept" href="#creation">Creating a Notification</xref></li>
  </ul>

<section>
      <title id="overview">Overview</title>
      <lines>
        This page provides information on the Notification Bar within the OpenStack Queuing Solution Tool (OQS).
      </lines>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title id="purpose">Purpose of this Feature</title>
      <lines>
        This feature notifies the user of any ongoing issues within the tool. Such issues may include:
      </lines>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <b>Pending bug fix:</b> If a bug exists in the tool, this Notification Bar will inform the user.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Third-party Software issues:</b> If a third-party piece of software is undergoing maintenance, has a bug or is offline,
          the Notification Bar will inform the user.
        </li>
      </ul>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title id="creation">Creating a Notification</title>
        <ol>
          <li>Notifications are created on the Upgrade Tool.</li>
          <li>On the Upgrade Tool, click on tools.</li>
          <li>click 'Edit' on the oqs-baseline.</li>
          <li>Enter message in <b>Notifications</b> field.</li>
          <li>(Optional) Enter the JIRA Issue in <b>Notification JIRA Issue</b> field.</li>
          <li>Click the <b>Notification Enabled</b> checkbox. <b>NOTE:</b> This will be automatically clicked (enabled) if the JIRA Issue is valid and not does have <b>Closed</b> status.</li>
          <li>Click the <b>Save</b> button. The notification will now show on the OpenStack Queuing Solution</li>
        </ol>
        <b>NOTES:</b>
        <ul>
          <li>Only Stratus team members have permissions to add and remove notifications.</li>
          <li>Once the issue has been resolved the notification can be removed by unclicking <b>Notification Enabled</b> checkbox or the check for the closed JIRA Issue will do this, from the Upgrade Tool.</li>
        </ul>
    </section>
  </conbody>
</concept>
