<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<task id="pods">
  <title>Pods</title>
  <taskbody>
    <context>
      <p>
        A Pod within the OpenStack Queuing Solution (OQS) represents an
        OpenStack Cloud. OQS provides Cloud Administrators the
        functionality to create unique configurations with regards to
        managing the deployment of different product types on shared tenant clouds.
      </p>

      <p>
        Cloud configurations are made up of the following parameters:
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          <b>Queue Product:</b> The Queue Product select allows a user
          to enable queuing based on the product/deployment variant within a given Pod.
          A user can select checkboxes for queuing all products, an individual product
          and or any combination of products.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Queuing Enabled:</b> A toggle to enable/disable the
          queue-handling of Deployments. When disabled, no 'Queued' Deployments
          can be set to 'Active'. This toggle has use-cases where, for example,
          a Cloud goes offline, and the Administrator wants no associated
          Deployment jobs to begin until it comes back online.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Pod Load Tolerance:</b> How many associated
          Deployments are permitted to run jobs concurrently. When this value
          is reached, any further Deployments become queued until there is enough load capacity
          available.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Load value</b> The capacity that product takes up from total Pod Load Tolerance.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Timeout value</b> This value is use to provide a given time to a Product to say how long it's Deployments can run in Active Deployment section, before next Queued Product's Deployment can start.
        </li>
        <li>
          <b>Install/Upgrade Metrics:</b>
           These metrics show the details of how many deployments are installed/upgraded successfully, failed, and timed out.<br/>
            <ul>
              <li>
              Deployment instances updated via the REST API with the status 'Finished', they will be automatically moved to Finished Deployments with a check icon
              and the Job Type based Successes metric will be incremented.
              </li>
              <li>
              Deployment instances updated via the REST API with the status 'Failed', they will be automatically moved to Finished Deployments with an exclamation icon
              and the Job Type based Failures metric will be incremented.
              </li>
              <li>
              If an active Deployment instance status is not updated via the REST API, its status will change to 'Timed-Out' after the default Product timeout or if set, Deployment custom timeout value has been exceeded.
               The Time-Outs metric will be incremented.
              </li>
            </ul>
        </li>
      </ul>

      <p><b>Radiator View</b></p>
      <p>The radiator view presents a visual representation of the queue
        status for every Pod in the OQS. A user can select specific Pods to monitor
        using the 'Custom View' tab in the radiator view. Each tile represents a Pod and displays
        current queue status and size. Pod tiles where queuing is disabled are
        greyed-out, while others are given a status colour of either green,
        yellow or red.
      </p>
      <p>
        The Pod tile warning colour indicators are determined based on the % of capacity used in the Pod.
      </p>
      <ul>
        <li>
          Green (Good): Pod total load at 70% or less.
        </li>
        <li>
          Yellow (Caution): Pod total load at 70% - 90%.
        </li>
        <li>
          Red (Warning): Pod total load over 90%.
        </li>
      </ul>
      <p><b>List View</b></p>
      <p>
        The list page provides a list-view for Pods, providing information on
        the settings applied for each Pod. Similar to the radiator page, the
        list page provides the same colour warning indicators depending on each
        Pods queue-status.<br/>
        <b>NOTE:</b> Admin users are only allowed to delete a Pod, using the "Delete" button. <br/>
        This button is only seen by Admins, login to access this button if you are Admin user.
      </p>

      <p><b>Objective</b></p>
      <p>Create a New Pod within the OpenStack Queuing Solution.</p>

      <p><b>Outline</b>
        <ol>
          <li>
            <xref href="#loginToOQS">Log-In to the OQS System</xref>
          </li>
          <li>
            <xref href="#openPodList">Open the Pods List View</xref>
          </li>
          <li>
            <xref href="#openCreatePod">Select the "Create" Button</xref>
          </li>
          <li>
            <xref href="#enterDetails">Enter the Pod Details</xref>
          </li>
          <li>
            <xref href="#savePod">Save</xref>
          </li>
        </ol>
      </p>
    </context>

    <steps>
      <step id="loginToOQS">
        <cmd>Log-In to the OQS System</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            Select the User tab in the nav bar, then select <b>"login"</b>.
            On submission of the required user login credentials, the user will
            be re-directed to the previous page.
          </p>
          <p>
            <b>Note:</b>OQS user sessions will remain active for 24 hours,
            unless the user manually terminates the session through logging out.
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="openPodList">
        <cmd>Open the Pod List View</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            Click on the Pod tab in the nav bar and then select
            <b>"List View"</b>.
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="openCreatePod">
        <cmd>Select the "Create" Button</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            Click on the <b>"Create New Pod"</b> button above the Pod list.
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="enterDetails">
        <cmd>Enter the Pod Details</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>Enter the details as shown below.</p>
          <p><b>Note:</b> Restrictions on the fields are as follows: </p>
          <ul>
            <li>
              <b>[MANDATORY] Name</b> must be a unique string between 5 and 20
              characters.
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Pod Load Tolerance</b> must be an integer
              greater than 0. <i>Default: Value taken from a Pod's default configuration, found under configurations area which is managed by Admins only.</i>
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Queue Enabled</b> is a flag value set to either "true" or
              "false". <i>Default: false</i>
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Queue Product(s)</b> is a select value set to either "All", an individual product
              and or any combination of products. <i>Default: "All"</i>
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Load Value</b> must be an integer greater than 0.
              <i>Default: Taken from configuration artifact, managed by Admins.</i>
            </li>
            <li>
              <b>Timeout Value</b> must be an integer greater than 0.
              <i>Default: Taken from configuration artifact, managed by Admins.</i>
            </li>

          </ul>
        </info>
      </step>
      <step id="savePod">
        <cmd>Save</cmd>
        <info>
          <p>
            Click the <b>"Save"</b> button to save the Pod details.
          </p>
          <p>
            <b>Note:</b>
            A User will be unable to save a Pod if any of the data supplied is
            invalid. Invalid data will be highlighted using red text.
          </p>
        </info>
      </step>
    </steps>

    <result>
      <p>
        The user will be redirected to the list view where it is
        possible to view recently defined and or existing Pod information.
      </p>
      <p>
        Users can view full details of any Pod selecting one from the tiles/list
        view provided.
      </p>
      <p>
        The <b>"edit"</b> button on this view-page directs logged-in users to an
        edit page where it is possible to modify the associated Pod information.
      </p>
    </result>

  </taskbody>
</task>
